Rimpa Choudhury

San Jose, CA | (978) 761-7919 | RimpaChoudhury@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rimpachoudhury/

Summary

Senior Software Development Engineer in Test with 10+ years of experience in QA strategy, automation frameworks, and delivery across FinTech, Cybersecurity, and Digital Identity Protection. Certified in AI & ML: Business Applications (UT Austin, McCombs). Skilled in Playwright, Cypress, Selenium, Appium, REST Assured, and Python. Experienced in LLM evaluation, RAG pipelines, and CI/CD automation.

Core Skills

Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript

Test Automation: Playwright, Cypress, Selenium, Appium, REST Assured, Cucumber, Karate

Performance & Security: JMeter, Burp, Lighthouse

Cloud & Data: AWS, Azure, Kafka, MySQL, Postgres, Aerospike

CI/CD & Tools: GitHub Actions, GitLab, Jenkins, Buildkite, Jira, TestRail, Zephyr, Datadog

AI/ML Tools: LangChain, RAG, DeepEval, Cursor, Flask, Streamlit

Professional Experience

Sr. SDET - Allstate Identity Protection | SF Bay Area

Feb 2024 - Present

- Member of Allstate Al Team focused on advancing AIP product initiatives.
- Architected and implemented a RAG pipeline, automating data ingestion, PII stripping, and transformation workflows from SQL/Mongo sources into Milvus Vector DB.
- Integrated AIP Llama3 embeddings to enable semantic search and AI-powered retrieval while ensuring data privacy & compliance using HashiCorp Vault and digital-privacy services.
- Deployed secure AI pipeline through Allstate infrastructure (APIGEE) and Azure OpenAI private endpoints for enterprise-scale LLM access.
- Used open source testing framework DeepEval to evaluate and test the LLM.
- Automated the REST API endpoints using Java, Karate and Cucumber frameworks.

Lead SDET - Nirvana. Money | SF Bay Area

Jun 2021 - Jul 2023

- As a Lead QE engineer, I laid down the quality vision, strategy, and plans and built the core automation framework that enabled us to do a beta launch of a brand-new digital bank and digital card in less than a year.
- Automated the entire Nirvana banking (neobank) and card application tech stack including calls to our partners (core banking systems, identity/fraud, credit underwriting – TransUnion).
- Built Playwright (JavaScript) test suites integrated with CI/CD (GitLab).
- Created GraphQL API tests using REST Assured.
- Developed mobile automation with Appium on BrowserStack/SauceLabs.
- Integrated test results with TestRail and bug metrics via Jira/GitLab.
- Performed performance testing with Google Lighthouse and PEN testing with Burp.

Software Engineering Lead in Test – LexisNexis / ThreatMetrix | San Jose, CA

Nov 2012 – Jun 2021 (9 years)

- As a QE Lead, responsible for all aspects of testing and automation for products spanning Data Engineering, Third-Party Integrations (ESB), Web Portal, and Machine Learning technologies.
- Led testing and automation for data engineering, APIs, and customer-facing Portal UI used by 3,000+ clients (Intuit, eBay, Amazon).
- Automated ESB integrations with 20+ partners (Apple, Google, Twilio, Telesign).
- Built portal REST API automation frameworks; created portal automation using Selenium/WebDriver with CI (Jenkins).

- Designed performance tests for SaaS systems with JMeter and monitored SLA compliance.
- Verified outputs of ThreatMetrix fraud scores generated by machine learning models, which were leveraged by companies like Facebook and Alipay to flag fraudulent transactions.
- Improved CI/CD processes, reducing deployment time by 70%.
- Mentored QE engineers and scaled automation across multiple products.
- Architected the entire software configuration management across all of our products using Puppet.
- Testing for Big Data stack includes: data streaming from Apache Apex apps, Kafka messaging, data ingestion (parquet files), and compaction across multiple sources such as Impala, Cassandra, Yellowbrick, Aerospike, etc.
- Worked closely with machine learning scientists on the ThreatMetrix Fraud Score model.

Sr. Software Engineer in Test - Netflix | Los Gatos, CA

Dec 2011 - Dec 2012

- Developed Selenium/WebDriver framework for Amazon cloud-based app with nightly CI runs.
- Built Android test automation framework for error simulations, reducing release cycle time by 75%.

Sr. Software Engineer in Test – Intuit Inc. | Mountain View, CA

Jan 2008 - Dec 2010

- Built Java/JEE white-box harness for payroll product, preventing critical production defects.
- Implemented acceptance tests with FitNesse, enabling business stakeholders to validate features directly.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin, McCombs School of Business Post Graduate Program in Al & ML: Business Applications Marathwada Institute of Technology, Maharashtra, India B.E. in Computer Science, with Honors

Additional Information

Work Status: U.S. Citizen